<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Energy = Milk · Coffee^2</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Energy = Milk · Coffee^2</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Anthony Hong.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 15:33:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hausdorff Measure, Dimension, and Analytic Capacity</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/analytic_capacity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 15:33:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/analytic_capacity/</guid><description>At the mid of Spring semester 2024, I began doing some readings with Prof. Henri Martikainen on Hausdorff measures and dimensions, fractals, and analytic capacity using Xavier Tolsa&amp;rsquo;s Analytic Capacity, the Cauchy Transform, and Non-homogeneous Calderón–Zygmund Theory, Pertti Mattila&amp;rsquo;s Geometry of sets and measures in Euclidean spaces: Fractals and rectifiability, and K. J. Falconer&amp;rsquo;s The Geometry of Fractal Sets.
Note on measures, dimensions, and AC.
Mandelbrot set
The image is from Medium.</description></item><item><title>Poincaré Universe</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/poincar%C3%A9-universe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:52:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/poincar%C3%A9-universe/</guid><description>Extract from A.B. Sossinsky&amp;rsquo;s Geometries 7.8 Hyperbolic Geometry and the Physical World
In his famous book Science et Hypothèse, Henri Poincaré describes the physics of a small &amp;ldquo;universe&amp;rdquo; and the physical theories that its inhabitants would create. The universe considered by Poincaré is Euclidean, plane (two-dimensional), and has the form of an open unit disk. Its temperature is $100^{\circ}$ Farenheit at the center of the disk and decreases linearly to absolute zero at its boundary.</description></item><item><title>Note on Information Theory</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/note_on_information_theory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 12:30:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/note_on_information_theory/</guid><description>I began a project with Dr. Bu on topic of quantum information geometry in summer of 2023. The following note is a short summary of Information Theory From Coding to Learning by Yury Polyanskiy and Yihong Wu plus self-contained preliminaries on probability theory.
Note on Information Theory.</description></item><item><title>Manifold Garden and Hilbert's Hotel</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/manifold-garden-and-hilberts-hotel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 10:00:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/manifold-garden-and-hilberts-hotel/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Manifold Garden&amp;rdquo; is really a marvel of puzzle game design, inviting players into an ethereal world where gravity is a toy and infinity a canvas. I played it during my freshman year and want to introduce you to this feast for the eyes.
Developed by William Chyr, this game stands as a monument to the beauty of architectural impossibilities (Hilbert&amp;rsquo;s hotel; see the end of this blog) and geometry (mostly Euclidena but also has a rubber-sheet flavour).</description></item><item><title>Covering Spaces of Wedge of Two Circles</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/covering-spaces-of-wedge-of-two-circles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 08:38:28 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/covering-spaces-of-wedge-of-two-circles/</guid><description>We start with some theorems from Hatcher&amp;rsquo;s algebraic topology and will give a solution of the following exercise by enumeration.
Find all the connected 2-sheeted and 3-sheeted covering spaces of $S^1 \vee S^1$​, up to isomorphism of covering spaces without basepoints. Review of Hatcher Proposition 1.32. The number of sheets of a covering space $p:(\widetilde{X}, \widetilde{x_0}) \to (X, x_0)$ with $X$ and $\widetilde{X}$ path-connected equals the index of $p_*\left(\pi_1\left(\widetilde{X}, \widetilde{x_0}\right)\right)$ in $\pi_1\left(X, x_0\right)$.</description></item><item><title>High-Dimensional Probability and Statistics II</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:53:24 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob2/</guid><description>This file is for the notes and exercises for the book Roman Vershynin&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Probability, one of the references used in Prof Lunde&amp;rsquo;s Math5440. The other references are Ramon van Handel&amp;rsquo;s Probability in High Dimension and Martin J.Wainwright&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Statistics.
Errata and update of HDP: errata, update.
Exercises solns for HDP: soln.
Exercises solns for HDS: soln.
3. Random Vectors in High Dimensions</description></item><item><title>Brahms and Strauss</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/brahms-and-strauss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:24:27 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/brahms-and-strauss/</guid><description>Post-romantic music, epitomized by the likes of Johannes Brahms and Richard Strauss, dives deep into a realm where intense emotions are paramount. Brahms&amp;rsquo; compositions resonate with a profound sense of grief, yet there&amp;rsquo;s a fiery undercurrent of rage that seems to threaten the very fabric of the world, as if it could tear it apart and reduce it to ashes. This emotional power, coupled with the structural legacies of Beethoven and Bach, makes his music enduringly impactful.</description></item><item><title>Schubert and Hilbert</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/schubert-and-hilbert/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:09:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/schubert-and-hilbert/</guid><description>The Austrian composer Franz Schubert&amp;rsquo;s response to Beethoven&amp;rsquo;s string quartets, &amp;ldquo;Now that such works have been composed, I have no regrets,&amp;rdquo; poignantly captures a moment of profound artistic realization and humility. This statement, made shortly before his untimely death at the age of thirty-one, reflects a deep sense of fulfillment and resignation. Schubert, in his brief life, grappled with the enormity of his own artistic contribution in the shadow of a colossus like Beethoven.</description></item><item><title>About Applied Math</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/about-applied-math/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:09:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/about-applied-math/</guid><description>There can be a common misconception about the phrase &amp;ldquo;applied math&amp;rdquo;. Contrary to the prevalent belief that applied mathematics involves the application of mathematics to other fields, it is actually the reverse. In reality, applied mathematics involves using concepts and methods from other disciplines within the framework of mathematics. This is better understood when considering the difference between the terms &amp;lsquo;applied math&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;mathematical application&amp;rsquo;. The former implies a broader scope where external concepts are integrated into mathematical contexts, while the latter suggests a more limited view where mathematics is merely applied as a tool in various fields.</description></item><item><title>High-Dimensional Probability and Statistics I</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 12:01:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob1/</guid><description>This file is for the notes and exercises for the book Roman Vershynin&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Probability, one of the references used in Prof Lunde&amp;rsquo;s Math5440. The other references are Ramon van Handel&amp;rsquo;s Probability in High Dimension and Martin J.Wainwright&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Statistics.
Errata and update of HDP: errata, update.
Exercises solns for HDP: soln.
Exercises solns for HDS: soln.
0. Appetizer Key Takeaways convex combination $\sum_{i=1}^m \lambda_i z_i \quad$ where $\quad \lambda_i \geq 0 \quad$ and $\quad \sum_{i=1}^m \lambda_i=1$.</description></item><item><title>Cayley Graphs on Surfaces</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/cayley-graphs-on-surfaces/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:09:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/cayley-graphs-on-surfaces/</guid><description>Some aspects may be related:
curvature of cayley graph
curavture of surface (The convergence result that for n going to infinity, the Ollivier-Ricci curvature of the random geometric graph sampled from manifold converges to the Ricci curvature of the manifold) (and for more general theory, see Graphs of Groups on Surface: Interactions and Models by Arthur T. White).
embedding of cayley graph on surface (see &amp;ldquo;Cayley maps&amp;rdquo; by R. Bruce Richter et al.</description></item><item><title>Geometric Group Theory</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/geometric-group-theory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:08:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/geometric-group-theory/</guid><description>There are some interesting materials in geometric group theory when I am doing research in computation of Ollivier-Ricci curvature of Cayley graphs:
Terrace Tao&amp;rsquo;s blog: he builds some analogies of geometric structure between group and manifold, including abelianness&amp;ndash;flatness (zero curvature), subgroups&amp;ndash;foliations, normal subgroups&amp;ndash;bundles&amp;hellip;
John Meier&amp;rsquo;s little blue LMS book: Groups, Graphs, and Trees: An Introduction to the Geometry of Infinite Groups. The book &amp;ldquo;proceeds step by carefully placed step, quite rapidly and naturally through many of the key ideas of modern geometric group theory,&amp;rdquo; reviewed by Jon McCammond, UCSB.</description></item><item><title>Website logistics</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/website-logistics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 19:29:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/website-logistics/</guid><description>After committing and pushing get stucked: for uncommited changes: git commit -m &amp;ldquo;Your commit message&amp;rdquo;
discard unstaged changes (note that directly copying from website will give a single - instead of consecutive two -): git checkout &amp;ndash; .
for &amp;ldquo;already exists&amp;rdquo; branch: git branch -d branch_name
use link to restore: rebrase and other commands.
To create a new blog: terminal (top of the mac computer) &amp;ndash; new terminal &amp;ndash; type hugo new blog/name.</description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/markdown-syntax-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/markdown-syntax-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a quick cheatsheet, check out &lt;a href="https://simplemde.com/markdown-guide">https://simplemde.com/markdown-guide&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Courses</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/course/</guid><description>Courses This is a collection of lecture notes, assignments, and some other related materials of the courses I have taken.
1. FL23-SP24 Math5031-5032 Algebra I-II, Prof. Beheshti Zavareh Thanks to Albert Peng for his permission to edit his tex file of Math5031 and also J.S. Milne’s tex file. The lecture note also adds many thoughts and exercises from other sources (see the bibliography).
Math5031-32 Lecture Note, with homework incorporated as solved exercises snake lemma.</description></item></channel></rss>