<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Readings on Energy = Milk · Coffee^2</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Readings on Energy = Milk · Coffee^2</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Anthony Hong.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 09:38:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Symplectic Geometry</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/symplectic_geometry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 09:38:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/symplectic_geometry/</guid><description>This reading file is for preparing the undergraduate thesis on Symplectic geometry and momental maps, supervised by Prof. Tang Xiang.
Our first reading is Ana Cannas da Silva&amp;rsquo;s Lectures on Symplectic Geometry (version: Jan 2006).
See overleaf for my partial notes.
Our second reading is Ana Cannas da Silva&amp;rsquo;s Symplectic Toric Manifolds (version: Jul 2001).</description></item><item><title>Processes, Wasserstein distance, and VC Dimension</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/random_and_empirical_processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 12:19:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/random_and_empirical_processes/</guid><description>This reading file draws various concentration results from chapter 7 and 8 of High-Dimensional Probability, and three applications of interest to be mentioned in this file are volume of polytopes, kantorovich-rubinstein duality for Wasserstein distance and VC dimension in machine learning.
Economist and Mathematician Kantorovich. Photo from St Petersburg University.
A stochastic process, or random process is a collection of $E$-valued random variables ${X_t:\Omega\to E}_{t\in T}$ with state space $(E,\mathcal{E})$ and parameter set $T$.</description></item><item><title>Concentration of Lipschitz Functions</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/concentration_of_lipschitz_functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:47:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/concentration_of_lipschitz_functions/</guid><description>The content comes from Lecture 7 of Prof. Lunde&amp;rsquo;s Math5440 and Chapter 5 of High-Dimensional Probability.
In first note on HDP, we introduced the bounded difference inequality, which is a result that can be applied to a wide range of problems. The bounded difference property may be thought of as a type of smoothness condition. Recall that a function $f: \mathbb{R}^d \mapsto \mathbb{R}$ is $L$-Lipschitz if the following holds for all $x, y \in \mathbb{R}^d$ , $|f(x)-f(y)| \leq L\Vert x-y\Vert $.</description></item><item><title>Hausdorff Measure, Dimension, and Analytic Capacity</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/analytic_capacity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 15:33:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/analytic_capacity/</guid><description>At the mid of Spring semester 2024, I began doing some readings with Prof. Henri Martikainen on Hausdorff measures and dimensions, fractals, and analytic capacity using Xavier Tolsa&amp;rsquo;s Analytic Capacity, the Cauchy Transform, and Non-homogeneous Calderón–Zygmund Theory, Pertti Mattila&amp;rsquo;s Geometry of sets and measures in Euclidean spaces: Fractals and rectifiability, and K. J. Falconer&amp;rsquo;s The Geometry of Fractal Sets. I also consulted Prof. Steven Krantz on more details of chapters in The Theory and Practice of Conformal Geometry.</description></item><item><title>Note on Information Theory</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/note_on_information_theory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 12:30:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/note_on_information_theory/</guid><description>I began a project with Dr. Bu on topic of quantum information geometry in summer of 2023. The following note is a short summary of Information Theory From Coding to Learning by Yury Polyanskiy and Yihong Wu plus self-contained preliminaries on probability theory.
Note on Information Theory.</description></item><item><title>High-Dimensional Probability and Statistics</title><link>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob_and_satistics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 12:01:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://AnthonyHongXiao.github.io/reading/high_dim_prob_and_satistics/</guid><description>This file is the first of the two for the notes and exercises in the book Roman Vershynin&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Probability, one of the references used in Prof Lunde&amp;rsquo;s Math5440. The other references are Ramon van Handel&amp;rsquo;s Probability in High Dimension and Martin J.Wainwright&amp;rsquo;s High-Dimensional Statistics. The file contains chapter 0,1,2,3,4, which cover some of the basic notions. We will use two other reading files for further topics, one for concentration of Lipschitz functions (chapter 5) and one for Random and Empirical Processes (chapter 7 and 8).</description></item></channel></rss>